hey guys Shan said welcome to concept
and coding uh so in today's video we
will be covering the remaining mappings
which are left like one to many many to
one and many to many but if you have
already seen the previous video where we
were discussed about one to one
unidirectional and by directional then
this video would be just a piece of cake
uh like nothing else like so very very
easy to understand that's what I'm
trying to say so let's start without
wasting any time like one too many
unidirectional
unidirectional you already know
reference exist only in One Direction
okay and one too many one entity
associated with multiple records in
another entity one to many like user can
have many orders one user many orders
okay so now let's say that if you
remember if you recall one to
one okay let's say you have a user and
address
okay so here you are restoring
the foreign
key remember like you are restoring the
foreign key of this ID user
ID now here in one to
many you have a user now let's say you
have an
order let's say this is user
one user one have let's say order one
order two order three now I want to
store the reference how you would store
it before understanding it just think
logically like how we will store it so
is it possible and I'm talking about
unidirectional all right so only one way
we have a reference so can we store in
the user like
U1 order one because here you have only
one row for the user next is user two
then you have user three so how you will
store it in one you have only one row
for user so we we can't store here right
because there can be many orders we
can't have one order right so one way is
we have a new
table where we St that hey this is user
one order one user one order two user
one order three like
this okay and what is the other way
other way is that here in this order
table itself I have one more more column
here we have user one this order two
also belongs to user one order three
also belongs to user one so these are
the two ways
so what is the default way in this way
so this is the default
way it creates a new
table and if you want if you don't want
to create a new table and if you want
this Behavior like in the order table in
the child one itself we want a foreign
key of the parent then we have to
specifically tell into the join column
okay we'll see so this is uh what I told
here that it creates a new table by
default
generally and you know that one too many
in the previous video I told you by
default It's a lazy loading and I have
already explained what is eager loading
and lazy
loading so just see this example now I
have created one entity user details
this is all we have
seen the user has let's say user ID
which are calling ID name
phone now in one to many I have also
have order details I have it stable this
order has let's say order ID which I'm
calling ID only and let's say product
name that's all and it's getter and
Setter now in one to many one user can
have many order rights so I have created
a list of orders inside this user detail
and now I have put one too many
annotation here okay now I am
telling jpa that it has one to many
relationship
means we have to handle the foreign key
but how so here by default what it will
do I told you what is the behavior it
will create a new
table okay and I also told you about the
casket type what would happen with the
casket type okay casket type merge
insert right similarly all means
whenever you will insert a user detail
order detail would also get inserted if
you delete the user detail parent the
child will also get
deleted so now here if you see what is
happening how is your user table going
to look like it has ID name and
phone ID name and phone
how is your order detail going to look
like ID and product name ID and product
name but where this one too
many is going to show default is it
should create a new table so here if you
see that it created a new table user
detail order detail it by default it
created okay and here if you see that
this is the IDS it created by default so
this is the ID and this is the
ID
okay but what if you don't want to
create a new table because in one to
many relationship I feel that this is
the better way like one user let's say
if user one have multiple
orders then the optimized way is that
you have multiple order one order one
order two order three here only we can
have like it belongs to user one this is
belongs to user one this is belongs to
user one and this is a foreign key of
here so this is the forign for key so
how to achieve this Behavior instead of
creating a new
table so nothing much we have to just
use at theate join column so in one to
one if you remember this we uses to
provide a name to the what name we want
to give to a foreign key
right here in one too many this also
been used to tell AP that we don't want
to store or we don't want to create a
new
table instead manage the foreign key
into the child table
itself okay so here now here if you see
everything same same everything with I'm
done is same only thing is this is added
newly add the join column okay
understand like who is storing a foreign
key then only it would be better clear
so here you have a user you have a order
so let's say order one order two here
you going to have a user one correct
so this one join column name what is the
name I'm giving user ID forign key
because this is the user ID foreign key
okay because this is the ID which going
to store and what is the reference
column name this over this table user
table ID what is the ID I'm calling user
ID
okay so this is the
ID okay so if you are clear that where
the foreign key is going to be created
in one to one it is used to create ha
itself inside a parent but in one to
many you know that parent can't hold it
because one too many one row can't you
can't have like zero uh uh order one
order two in one so it has to create a
new table but we don't want a new table
to create it that's why we are using at
theate join column
which
enforce jpa to add it into the child
itself and we tell that hey this is the
name of the column we wanted for the
foreign key and it is reference to this
column
ID okay so now how it's going to look
like in the user detail what you're
going to see ID name phone ID name phone
and in the order detail you will have ID
product name and also this foreign key
okay
and this warrant key is the name user _
idore FK is the name what we give and
this is tied up with this user ID
reference ID is the user ID we
give
okay now if you do a first insert call
now now I am calling user I am trying to
do an insert so user has name phone and
a list of orders it has a list of orders
right so I'm providing an orders I am
giving two IAM and cold ring so if you
see my order entity one is ID which is
autogenerated another is only product
name so I'm giving like since it's a
list I am giving an array and inside
that I am creating two objects one is
ice cream one is cold ring once you hit
it so here if you see data is inserted
and it even so it created a user and it
now you got a user ID and even it
created an order two orders and also
created an order IDs also for them so
here if you see user is
created and this two order is created
one is ice cream one is cold
ring and here if you see the foreign key
is updated properly one so its parent is
one so one to
many okay depending so see in one to
many use case my recommendation would be
this one instead of creating a new table
okay generally new table we create in
many to many scenario
only okay in one if you have a use case
in one to many it's better you could add
it here itself otherwise you have to
maintain one more table and maintaining
one more table you like it has its own U
Advantage
disadvantage but I would say that in in
one too many use case generally this is
you can say that the better readable and
faster way of accessing the
data okay now if I want to do get call
now I want to do get Call of it so what
would happen so here if you see this is
just a controller I have added uh so
that you can easily understand it better
I think in one 12 one uh I have already
explained this like dtos and all so here
if you
see one too many I already told you
right by default is
lazy okay so this is the get call so now
here if you see first I am doing find by
ID whatever the ID I am fetching it my
expectation is since I am doing user
controller user has let's say three
Childs order one order two order three
so here I'm first fetching the user so
so it will only fetch user not orders at
at this point of time only user is
fetched not
order then I am saying that going to map
user details to user dto so now I am
going to construct the dto so now here I
am constructing the
dto so in the dto construction I am
putting ID name phone now here I'm
printing one message going to query
order table here now you know that in
the lazy whenever we are going to access
it like get me the order details then it
will hit on one more select
query one more select query on order
table and then it will F the order
details so we can see the output I did
one get call so here I am doing one get
call I've got the data but here if you
see first it make a select query on only
from user table so it first fetch
only user data then it printed this
going to map user detail to user
D going to map user detail to user dto
then internally here while doing a
mapping it is first printing going to
query order table here now going to
query order detail now when I
specifically did get me the order
details now at this point of time it
will hit an order
and it f the data and
return so you can if you remember if you
haven't watch the previous video you
might be thinking hey why I am creating
dto it just to Showcase you how lazy
working because if I am just returning
it from here right uh from this itself I
will return let's say return output here
itself okay now what would happen is you
will still get the same output you will
get the order itself but there you get
confused CH that hey it's a lazy then
why this order get
comes because because of
serialization okay when you do a uh Json
uh when in the response we return a Json
right so our Jackson internally call get
API so even though we are not calling
Jackson internally call the get right
here we have the Getters and Setters
right gets and Setters so here
internally it calls get order details so
intern
Jackson invokes it so to avoid the
confusion to show that how lazy working
at what exactly
time the order is getting fetched when
specifically we want maybe your scenario
you don't want to return the order
details then you don't have to uh do
this and no order query would be
hid
okay eager fetch you already know that
if you want eagerly you can simply put
uh F Type eager and simply return find
by ID you don't have to do dto like it
will always return full itself and in
the query itself you can double verify
now the select query is like from user
table now join with the order table
earlier it was only from user table in
the lazy
one okay and the casket type I have
already explained you in the previous
video with the example that persist
merge remove all all works in the same
scenario right so now here whatever the
casket type we are using
right casket type all so
means when you create a new user if
there are an order it will also get
created if you use remove you remove the
user then all its Associated order will
also get removed if you update it if
there is an Associated order and you are
trying to update it that will also get
updated and if you want all this feature
you can use
all okay so this one I have also
explained you in the previous one now
there is this is one very interesting uh
is something called orphan removal now
with one to
many there is one question comes that
okay this is my
user user
one this user
has order one order two order three
order 4 user one user one user one user
one okay now it is possible that in
future I am updating that user one has
only order one order two and order
three I am removing the order four from
the collection
here if you see in the
user in the
user you are maintaining a list right
list of order details where is it you
are maintaining a list inside a user you
are maintaining a list what if you
update this list and instead of four
orders you are just having now one
order here instead of four uh four
orders you updated the collection and
now you have only three orders and now
you are calling save you are not calling
delete you are just calling save again
okay maybe you can say that
update you are calling
update
so if you are not doing orphan removal
what would happen
is this will change to null but this
will not delete so this will become orun
now earlier user one has all four orders
later on you
updated only that okay order one order
two order three is there in the
collection order four you have removed
from the collection in the Java code and
you call Save again internally save see
that a ID is already there so internally
try to update it so for order four it
will change it to null it will remove it
because now it is not there in the
collection but this would be known as
orphan this would be known as now or
orphan because it doesn't have any
parent and this is generally we are
calling as a child table so that's where
we call it orphan removal any orphan
child you have remove it okay so that's
where automatically removes child entry
when child remove from the parent
collection okay so just see this example
this is just a controller I'm just
created this a testing uh even though
it's a get don't worry about it this is
just for the testing the orphan so I
have created first insert user so we
will create two orders user order one
order
two okay after that I will invoke this
API and in that one I will first Fest
the data user details and it is um it
will get all the data right now I'm
doing get order details right so all
this user one both the orders will come
and I'm removing the zero index I am
removing this and I'm again saving it
remember I not deleting it I'm just
saving it means I am updating it because
it has the ID so internally it will go
for that
update so what would happen let's see
that first I'm inserting it so here this
is the post API I'm inserting one user
has two orders ice cream and cold ring
so now in the user detail one user is
created and two orders is
created okay both has the foreign key
properly
set now I am testing orphan removal So
currently orphan removal by default is
false only by default is
false okay so means we are testing an
existing Behavior till now what we are
doing now I am calling the other API
this API which I'm calling you so what
it will do it will first fetch it remove
one order and then save it so means
order one is now
orphan so now here if you see that order
one is not coming into the response user
detail has one user order detail still
has two but here if you see one is
considered as null now zero one because
I am removing it I am removing the zero
so I am remov the one from the
collection
so this one got updated to null so now
this become orphan it doesn't have any
parent
okay so
now so here if you see right you can
check the console how it works
so it first did a select
okay since it's a lazy one so it didn't
it only hit user table then after that I
did this get order details right so at
this point of time it hit the order
table so from there I removed one zeroth
index order I removed from the
collection and I call Save
internally it will call update only so
here it is calling update and Order
detail this one is setting null one is
setting null because I have removed it
from the collection
now if I want orphan removal
functionality then what we can do is in
one too many casket type all there is
one more field like rund removal equals
to true so we can set
it so what would happen
now the same API we are hitting again
the same output but if you see the DB
now user detail yes order detail now
only one
the orphan which was an ice cream in
that
scenario got removed deleted so now here
if you see the query also you will see
one delete query
also okay so orphan removal true equals
to we are telling jpa that hey if you
are seeing that we are removing an
entity so you remember right persistence
context everything is in memory like so
user has
order one order two okay everything is
in memory now you are removing order one
from the collection so persistence
context everything has known about it
and now when you're calling jpa update
it knows
that this order has been removed from
the user collection so first it update
it to
null first it updated to
null and then later on it deleted it
so it's a two-step process but that jpa
will take care of removing the
orphan child so if anybody in interview
asks you about this like um what are the
challenge comes in one to many uh it's
orphan removal this is how we can handle
it and sometime it also ask that how it
is different from casket delete and
orphan removal
caset delete and orphan removal see both
are different Concept in casket delete
means you are so user has two Childs
order one order two in casket delete
means you are deleting the parent and
caset it will delete the child also that
what caset delete is okay if you
deleting the parent child will also get
deleted orphan removal is you are
removing a child
you are removing the child from The
Collection not from the DB you are not
deleting the child from the DB you're
removing from The Collection only okay
then we have to tell jpa that remove it
from the DB also that's what orphan
removal
is okay and orphan you already know that
without parent in this scenario your
child table child row doesn't have any
foreign key which points to the parent
okay I hope this is clear uh if this is
clear then we can move to bidirectional
that is again a very very simple but
again an important concept one too many
bidirectional if you are clear with the
one to1 B directional then it would be
less confusing for you here but before I
proceed further I will tell you that
there are three four things parent
child then another is your
oing and
inverse side oing side inverse side
don't get confused that hey parent is
always the owing side child is always
the inverse side
no you know that parent and child
concept right like depends in your
business which is considered as a parent
and which is considered as a child like
parent if parent exist then only child
can
exist okay if child existence is depend
upon parent so parent child relationship
we can determine from the situation to
situation because we can easily identify
that yes child dependency is on parent
if parent goes child also goes but what
is oing side and inverse side don't get
confused with that oing is always parent
inverse is also child
no oing means is those which site
contains the foreign
key which site contains the foreign key
inverse is like the which side do
not contains the foreign
key simple easy to
remember so oing side is holds the
foreign key relationship in a
table inverse side is no foreign key is
created in the table
in one 12 one we have a parent table we
have a child table in one to one B
directional you know that foreign key is
created here in the parent
key we go one to one so this is your
parent row this is your
address let's say user address so
address ID so here inside this parent is
now the owing side but now in one too
many you have a user you have an
order okay user one user two here you
have order one order two belongs to user
one order two belongs to user one order
three belongs to user two so this is
your foreign key now here so who is the
owing side this one is
the oing side now your child is now your
oing side and this is the inverse side
doesn't hold the prime uh foreign
key okay so always easy to remember uh
which one is oing side and which one is
reward
side so in one to many bidirectional so
here if you
see in the oing side we always write at
the join column okay because in
unidirectional you know that only one
side we keep it okay but now in the oing
uh by Dire we have two side inverse side
and oing side so generally join column
is put into the oing side which holds
the primary key okay so now in the order
details user has many orders order one
order two order three so now here if you
see that order details you have an ID
product name and one
user also one remember one one more
thing B directional doesn't change your
DB structure like a
unidirectional in a unidirectional in a
bidirectional the
table structure would remain the
same you have a user you have an
order you have a user ID here you have
an order ID here you have a product and
here only also you have one user foreign
key like in unidirectional same here but
here what happen happen is here in the B
directional you have reference from the
both
side one is like maintain into the table
and another is on the Java object side
itself so now here if you see which one
is your oing side oing side is the one
which holds the foreign key foreign key
is holds by your child table order okay
we are saying that order is my child
table so now here I have ID I I have
product now I am creating a user details
user okay because one order can have
only one
user
okay one order can have only one user
this
way so that's why so what is the foreign
key name join key column user ID oing FK
this is the name I want to give and what
is the column at point to user ID this
one in the user table user ID this is
pointing to this
ID okay and this is just a getter
Setter nothing much and here in the
inverse side now your inverse side is
your currently here parent which do not
holds a foreign
key so here you have an ID name phone
and here I have a list of orders list of
orders and now since it inverse side so
that's why I am using one to many here
map by user
detail so notice one more
thing here parent to child here is one
to many one user has many child and
there many to one okay many orders can
have only one
parent okay so that's why many to one
annotation is used
here okay so at the inverse side
I am using map by user details so this
will tell jpa that this side is not
handling the foreign key this is just
like a reference in the Java code in the
Java code you can access the order
details here from this side also and
from there user details this side also
but this is the one oing side where we
have a join column this is the one which
actually responsible for creating a
foreign key in the table
okay and this is just a map by user
details that this is
uh just a reference to this
one and this is all our getter
seter okay so first thing is
clear which one is your oing side which
one is your inverse side at the oing
side okay so here here in this case in
one to many your child is your oing side
which holds the foreign key so that's
why you put many to one annotation first
part second part is you use the join
column at the oing side and you can give
proper what is the name you wanted and
the respective column in the parent
which is pointing to okay and in the
corresponding parent table which is do
not hold the foreign key so it's an
inverse side and there we have to use
one to many and we have to give just
it's a map by okay and uh it is mapping
to this one okay so means jpa it will
tell jpa that uh we don't have to uh
create any foreign key column here just
a map by in Java code itself it would be
used okay it is not maintaining any
foreign key so first is clear second is
I already told you in the previous video
Json identity info like when in case of
bir
directional during serialization
recursion issue can come so there are
many scenarios you can use Json ignore
right and there are other ways so
identity info we can use it like this
okay so this is the second way this we
have already discussed in the previous
video why we needed it to stop the
recursion because during serialization
user now has reference to order order
now has reference to user so it should
not go
continuously and now here if you see the
third last scenario here is
during set orders we are setting this
here so what we are actually doing here
so now here if you
see see this with this
example I am creating a user I am
creating a user and name phone number
and this user has two orders ice cream
and cold drink placing a two
order you know that casket typ is all so
means child t will also get created okay
so user would be created and child would
be
created now here if you see from the
user we are creating a user right so
child table how it will create it will
call set order internally right now if
we just call set order here if you do
this
only this two things would come null
why because in the bir directional this
is your invers
side here we are telling jpa that this
is just a map by this is not maintaining
any foreign key
relationship you don't have to worry
about at this
class so during when you are creating an
order from this two rows it will create
set
orders what should be the value which
going inside
this it doesn't know it won't
automatically jpa would add because jpa
is not maintaining this as like a
maintaining a foreign key okay only this
one oing one man to one where we have
put a join column it is maintaining that
here this is map by which is the inverse
so here whatever the order we have order
details so what I'm doing is I'm
iterating over an order and I am putting
user details this so I'm inserting the
reference of this user Det
details that whatever the user I am
creating whatever the order you are
creating this order has user details
this one this user and that's where this
one is coming here at both
side okay that's why this one is coming
at both
side so if you understand oing and
inverse then this things understanding
this thing would be very easy for you
that why we are doing what okay when we
have to where where we have to use join
columns okay uh in one two in a
unidirectional it's very easy we have to
use at one side only okay but in B
directional it become confusing where we
have to use so always use it at the oing
side other at the maap you have to take
care of the uh like any mapping you have
to do you have to
do in one 121 bir directional we are not
doing this because our PA has owing the
foreign key right so jpa will take care
of it so even though we are putting
address right just setting an address it
will take care of uh inserting the
address ID properly foreign key properly
because this is our primary
itself uh parent table itself is your o
site so if you are creating a user that
table itself has a foreign key so jpa
will manage it but here in this one to
many scenarios this is inverse side now
so jpa will not take care of uh filling
up the order ID uh foreign key filling
up the foreign key here so we have to
maintain
it okay similarly you can call user join
it will properly come and no recursion
problem will come also because recursion
problem we have solved through this Json
identity info also you can use Json
ignore if you want generally if you ask
my preference Also let's say user us has
order order has
user so generally at one side you can
always put like Json
ignore generally in the child side we
can always put Json ignore from parent
side we can have an order from Child
side we can put Jason ignore we don't
want uh again the parent information
parent information we have already taken
out but it depend upon your business
logic how you are accessing General
from parent we access the child detail
that's why we don't want parent details
again and that's why we put Json ignore
and the child
one one to one many to one uni
directional before I go to many to one
unidirectional many to
one bir
directional is same as what we did just
now
one to many bidirectional right it is
also equivalent to many to one bir
directional see whenever we are talking
about one to many we are saying that
parent to child and when we are talking
about many to one generally depending
upon the concept generally we are
talking about child to
parent okay so here in this case
bidirectional child to parent
bidirectional in this case let's say
user or order
scenario now if I have to use many to
one I this is my many I'm talking hey
many order has one
user many order has one user now I have
changed the way of take talking or my
perceptive now in one to many I was
talking from parent to child now in many
to one generally it goes in a reverse
Direction like many
orders one user but still user is my
driving uh like user is my driving one
like it is the considered as a parent so
many to one bidirectional is exactly
same as generally one to many
bidirectional same piece of code would
be written because here if you see
whichever is the oing party that would
have man to one here annotation and the
inverse side we'll have one too
many okay so only little slightly
difference come in many to one
unidirectional that is also very very
similar to your one to many okay so now
here if you see
that we'll see this with an example you
will get to know easily okay I will
first tell you about this table entity
yeah so earlier we were talking about
one user can have many order order one
order two one two many now we are
talking about multiple orders can
belongs to one user many to one it's the
same thing right just way of seeing the
program is
different
now if you see this user details I am
not putting anything I have user ID name
phone now here if you see parent doesn't
know about child in one too many parent
know about the child because here we
have a list of
orders now in this many to one we are
talking from the child perspective so
here if you see parent doesn't know
about what is the like how many Childs
are there user ID name phone that's
all but in the order details it it know
about a parent and here we have put many
to one casket type all join column we
can say that this is
the you know that table wise also
exactly same child table only will
contain the foreign key order details
only contain the foreign key and this
foreign key belongs to the
ID okay exactly same as one to many only
thing that there in one to many your
parent has about knowledge of the child
list of order and here we are using one
to many now in many to one your parent
doesn't know about your child your child
knows about your parent and we are using
many to one annotation here but but DB
schema wise exactly same and B
directional is exactly same as one to
many
bidirectional okay so you can try it out
exactly it just same it just way of
talking like um one to many many to one
it's just like from parent to child
child to parent that's
all and then we have many to many uni
directional so now here in this case you
need to understand many to
many there is no parent child
concept okay anybody based upon your
business can be treated as a parent can
be treated as a
child similarly can be treated as an
owing can be treated as an
inverse both can be oing both can be
inverse like you can take any one of
them as an owing side any one of them as
an inverse side because many to
many reference on it's a uni Direction
means one way only now see
that let's say you have product one
product
two
okay one uh so many to many so here if
you see that order one order
two order one can also have product one
and product two order two can also have
product one and product
two okay so now here if you
see product one is associated with order
one
and product one is associated with order
two similarly order one is associated
with product one and product two so we
have many to many relationship here no
one is dependent on
anybody
so ordered details and here I'm creating
one more entity product details in order
I have nothing but an order number which
is
autogenerated and since this is we are
talking about unidirectional means
I want to reference from one side itself
so I want from order two
product like I want to in the code wise
I want to from DB schema wise
unidirectional bidirectional you know
that exactly same no difference only
thing is Java code how you can reference
like how you can access it so in unit
Direction I want let's say I'm putting
inside an order from order I can reach
all product one product
two so that's why I put list of product
details means order is
knowing about all the products and
inside a product you have a product ID
what is the name what is the price but
you can only move in one direction from
order to
product like here in in One Direction
only
okay so how you can you know and one
more thing you know that you have an
order table
you have let's say order one order two
you have a product
table you have a product one product two
now you have to associate it with order
one is associated with product one
product two how you can store it in can
you store it here can you store it in
the child table there is no child parent
relationship so in many to many always
we create a new table order one product
one order one product two order two
product one order to product two or
product three so now this is how many to
many in a new table we
create so that's why there is something
called list of products because one
order can be associated with many
products so now I am putting at the rate
many to many relationship now we are
telling to the jpa that it's a many to
many and I'm since it has to create a
new table so we you can tell this at
theate join
table what is the table name I want to
create I want to create order uncore
product this is the name I want to give
order undor product and this foreign key
right one foreign key in order one
foreign key product so that's why join
column you can make anybody as uh oing
and anybody has inverse I'm telling you
so join column one I'm killing order ID
inverse join column is your product ID
this
one okay so two columns it will create
into this new table like
this and this is just a getter Setter so
now here if you see your order details
is just your order
number which is
autogenerated your product details is
product ID name price product ID name
price and now because of this many to
manyi mapping a new table order
underscore product would be
created which has two column one is
order ID and one is product ID order ID
and product
ID okay we can test it
life so here I have simply created a
rest controller product
controller okay and I have created one
order controller so very very simple so
here if you see just see what I am doing
here I will one by one I will tell you
let's say step one create a
product so I am hitting a product API /
API SL product/ API SL product so this
is the
insert product method is getting
involved product has uh name and price
right so I am first creating one product
and then I'm creating second product
cold ring so two product I am creating
so product is created I got an ID so in
the DB now here if you see that two
products are now there in my schema in
the DB currently no order is
there so first step I did is created two
products now I creating an order now
here if you
see insert order when I am creating an
order now let's say that order one so
product one and product two I already
have in a DB okay now this order one I
am saying that hey associate this order
with this product product one and
product two let's say I have more
product P3 P4 but in order one I want to
associate it with only P1 and P2 so mean
I'm passing the
ID so first it will
fetch product
IDs once it will fetch the product ID it
will add into the orders set product
details and then I am saving giv the
order okay so here in my
product uh here in my order detail I
have a list of product
details okay so that's where I am
setting it
like now if you see it would become more
clear with
this now I creating an order so this is
the first order API I'm
creating so order has only order number
which is autogenerated right this is
autogenerated rest is like the list of
product list of product so I am passing
a list of product now here I have
already created two products one is ice
cream which has id1 and another id2 is
cold
ring so I'm just passing that hey
Associated this order with this product
ID product ID one and here product ID 2
so what my code will
do from this order which request is
coming it will take out the ID
D and it will search so first ID one I
am sending right this ID
one this ID one so for this ID one it
will first go and from the DB it take
outs its
details then it's a stream right then it
goes second and then it will take out
its detail and it will collect into this
list okay now I have the complete list
of this uh product ID 1 and similarly
product two which is for cold rink and
its price and here we have ice cream and
its price
100 now I am inserting into my order
details and I am saving it
now okay so
now what is the expectation here here if
you see the response my order is created
one and it is associated with the
existing product itself so currently I
have achieved this one order one already
I have product one product two it is
associated with this
now now I am creating another order okay
so orders are order number is
autogenerated so on successful order
number two would be created but I am
associating it with product only product
ID 2 so what would happen with the code
is that it will take out a product ID it
will find so it will get this detail
product to in the list and save
it okay so what it will do
is it will return like this now if you
see the DB order detail two orders
created product detail only two product
which we initially created and in the
order product which is a new table there
I have like with one order product one
one order product two and with the
second order only product two is
associated okay and here if you
see we are inserting an order now here
if you
see uh where it goes entity yeah this
order we are this is maintaining the
like here we have a join table many to
many relationship okay so means jpa
knows
that it has to fill up this IDs foreign
key and product ID so that's where we
are not worry about our code itself that
okay
update order ID and product ID
properly okay because in this class
itself it will create uh it will create
a new
table it has this two
fields and jpa is maintaining it it is
not map by so we don't have to worry
about that properly order ID product
product ID is set jpa will take care of
it if it is a maap byy let's say that if
it is a mapped by then we have to set
then jpa will not take care of setting
the order ID product
ID okay since uh this is foreign key is
properly maintaining by jpa we don't
have to worry about so this getter
Setter itself we can rely
easily okay so now here if you see that
we are achieving many to many
relationship
properly and now in the bir directional
you know that DB structure is going to
be the same no difference only thing
differ
is now we have a reference from both
side we have a
user or we have an order and we have a
product okay we can go from order to
product from product to order but now
here in this scenario many to many can
you tell me which one is oing and which
one is
inverse first of all there is no child
and parent Concept in many to many of
product is not dependent on order order
is not dependent on product first of all
okay both are independent if one goes
down or one goes deleted other one not
get deleted
right and who can keep the foreign key
so here if you see
nobody here we create a new
table where is this new
table here here we create a new
table okay neither product is keeping
the foreign key neither order is
creating a foreign key so we can give
ownership of anybody we can make any one
as an oing and another one as an
inverse so let's say that I'm keeping
the order as an oing itself so there I
am putting like this like order has a
list of
product so I am putting exactly the same
many to
many new table created and this is the
two IDs it has to create exactly
same and product details now here if you
see this three table now it's the invert
also right so list of orders also but I
want
to create it inverse so map by so I have
created many to many here
also map by this product details this
one okay DB schema wise no difference
exactly
same only thing is like uh in the Java
code how you can reference it which one
you want to keep as an oing which one
you want to keep as an
inverse oing generally contains the
foreign
key okay so here nobody contains the
foreign key new table is created so it's
just like you want to give
responsibility to order detail entity to
create a new table or product to create
a new table here I'm creating an order
uh responsibility to create a new table
that's all nothing
much and whenever you will create an
order
okay it will take care automatically
update product ID and Order ID
Associated
properly but now here if you say this is
map
buy okay it is also have list of orders
so now let's say if you are creating a
product and product also has list of
order one order two like this inverse
you are
doing will it properly create uh fill up
this table will it properly fill up this
table no it will not it will create
product it will create order but will it
take care of this foreign key properly
update no you have to take care of it
filling in this table because it's a map
by like it's only Java reference jpa is
not managing the DB
here here at theate join and this is not
map by so jpa takes care of
responsibility when you go for order and
from order you are creating
products properly ID would be created
foreign key would be updated but Vice
vers now here product you have product
one let's say ice cream and you are
creating the associated with two
orders it will not update the foreign
key table properly because it's just a
map so you have to write your properly
in the setter code that update the
foreign key
also okay so based upon your business
logic
how generally operation comes like
product is always there product one
product two and orders now coming in
your
system okay so it's better that you make
it an owing site so always based upon
your business
logic depends like which one is going to
be the oing which one is going to be the
inverse if you
make opposite you blindly choose anyone
as an owing and anyone as an inverse
then you have to take care of
responsibility of updating the foreign
key properly that's the only thing you
have to consider in the
bidirectional okay with that being said
all the mappings are completed but do
practice it out uh it's all easy but if
you practice it with your hand you will
get proper clarify like okay to whom we
are saying oing to him we are saying
Inver w why one to many many to one is
so related to each other it's just about
the concept when we are saying one to
many parent to child many to one
sometimes child to parent it's just way
of saying okay so it it creates a lot of
confusion but they are very tightly
related to each other okay guys so last
topic left in jpa which is your custom
queries right and criteria queries we
will cover that soon also and after that
we will start with Spring Security okay
guys thank you bye